見つけたぞ　人虎
I've found you, weretiger.
Akutagawa!
芥川
Looks like you've improved your
acrobatic skills, weretiger.
曲芸の腕は上げたようだな　人虎
Why are you here, Akutagawa?
何をしに来た　芥川
貴様を殺しに
To kill you.
Don't you understand the
situation we're in right now?
今がどんな時かわかっている筈だ
僕達の居場所がなくなるかもしれないんだぞ
We may no longer have a place to live.
僕にはお前が微塵も理解できない
I don't understand you one bit.
I don't remember ever asking
for your understanding.
理解を求めた覚えはない
やれやれ
Oh, dear.
芥川君の独走癖は相変わらずだなぁ
Akutagawa-kun still has a
terrible habit of going solo.
仕方ない
All right.
敦君
Atsushi-kun, we don't have
time to deal with him.
彼に係っている暇はない　先に進もう
Let's move on.
But...
ですが…
Don't worry.
大丈夫　私の云う通りにすれば逃げられるよ
Just do as I say, and you'll make it.
わかりました
Understood.
Akutagawa, I'm speaking to
Dazai-san on this intercom.
芥川
このインカムは太宰さんと繋がってる
He wants to talk to you.
話があるそうだ
Dazai-san!
太宰さん
やあ　ゼルダ　元気にしてたか
Well hello, Zelda.
How have you been?
Yeah, I apologize for calling you so late.
あぁ　電話が遅れたのは謝るよ
I heard the news.
聞いたぞ　またシェフを解雇したのか
You laid off another chef?
せっかく欧州の最高級レストランから…
They came all the way here from
a top-notch European restaurant.
いや　責めてなんかいないさ　本当だ
No, I don't blame you.
It's true.
君のクリームチーズ嫌いを知らない料理人なんて
Any cook that doesn't know of your distaste
for cream cheese ought to perish.
世界から滅びればいい
そう　あの子はまだロンドンに留学中だ
Yes, she's still studying in London.
勿論あの子のことも一秒だって忘れやしないさ
I wouldn't forget it for a moment.
Sorry, it appears I have a guest.
悪いが　客人のようだ　また電話する
I'll call you back.
I love you, Zelda.
愛してるよ　ゼルダ
That was a brief farewell, boy.
短い別れだったな　少年
捜し物は　これか
Is this what you're looking for?
貴方が制御端末を守るガード？
Are you the one guarding
the control terminal?
Here's the first secret
to how I got this far.
俺がここまで登り詰めた成功の秘訣その一だ
仕事で一番大事な部分は他人任せにしない
The most important part of any job is to
not leave anything for others to handle.
ところで　この「白鯨」の重量を知っているか
By the way, do you know how
much the Moby Dick weighs?
総重量二万九千トン
It has a total mass of 29,000 tons.
Dropped from an altitude of two kilometers,
上空２キロから落すれば
TNT爆弾百四十トン相当のエネルギーが
it would explode with the force of 140 tons of TNT...
Right in the middle of the city.
市内のど真ん中で炸裂する
そんな非道…絶対に許されない
No one would allow such an atrocity.
The second secret to how I got this far is:
don't let the values of others affect you.
秘訣その二
他人の価値観に流されるな
とはいえ　君も俺も忙しい
With that said, you and I are both busy.
If we have to fight over the control
terminal, let's keep things simple.
その制御端末を奪い合うなら　簡潔に行こう
三つ数えたら同時に走り　先に端末を手にしたほうが勝者
We'll both run towards it
on the count of three.
The first of us to take it is the winner.
If you win, you can do as you like
with the Moby Dick.
君が勝てば　「白鯨」は好きに動かせ
だが俺が勝てば　君は俺に服従し　捜し物を手伝ってもらう
But if I win, you'll serve me
in helping with my search.
ワン
One...
勝負に乗って　合図と同時に走るか
Should I take his challenge
and run when he does?
Two...
ツー
No, I can't trust anyone from
the Guild to keep a promise.
いや　ギルドの口約束なんて信用できない
裏をかいて合図より前に奪い
I'll outsmart him and take it
before his signal, and run!
そのまま逃げる
スリー
Three.
秘訣その三
Secret number three: It's easy to predict the
behavior of anyone who's given an opportunity.
好機を与えられた人間の行動は読みやすい
Oh? You aren't going down with that kick?
今の蹴りで倒れんか　大したものだ
That's impressive.
Very well.
いいだろう　一万では失礼だったな
10,000 may have been insulting.
This is a portion of my securities.
これは俺が所有する有価証券の一部だ
There's 100,000 dollars worth.
十万ドルある
I haven't introduced you
to my ability yet, have I?
俺の異能力　紹介がまだだったな
Ability: The Great Fitzgerald.
異能力　「華麗なるフィッツジェラルド」
俺の異能力は
My ability grants me physical
strength equal to the money I spend.
消費した金額に比例して　身体能力を強化させる
Be proud, boy.
誇っていいぞ　少年
I haven't used 100,000
dollars in a long time.
十万も使うのは久し振りだ
Of course, Zelda would spend
that much in a month.
もっともゼルダなら　ひと月で消し飛ばす額だがな
これで凡て予定通りだ
Now everything is going according to plan.
With crashing the Moby Dick,
and with capturing you.
「白鯨」の落下も　君の捕獲もな
ぼ…僕も…
Me?
うちの作戦参謀は
Our strategist has the
ability to make
手持ちの情報から未来を限定予言できる異能力者だからな
limited precognitions based
on what information she has.
Now that I have you, it would
be a pain if you got away.
却説　捕らえたはいいが
また逃げられたら面倒だ
念の為　手足を外しておくか
I should probably remove your
arms and legs for good measure.
おや　珍しい客人だ
Oh my, what an unusual guest.
Mister...
ミスターアグラ…
Agua?
Aguagar?
アーグラーか
芥川
Akutagawa.
That's the one.
それだ
Episode Twenty-Three
Rashoumon, The Tiger,
and The Last Emperor
Hey, Kyouka-chan, can you hear me?
やあ　鏡花ちゃん　聞こえるかい
It's Dazai.
太宰だ
特務課と交渉してね　取り敢えず君を地上に降ろせることになった
We negotiated with the
Gifted Special Operations Division.
We can bring you back down for now.
その無人機の操縦方法を教えるよ
I'm going to teach you
how to pilot that drone.
もういい
No more.
本当のことを云うとね
To tell you the truth, the Agency
doesn't have a reason to rescue you.
探偵社には君を救助する理由がないのだよ
You aren't an official member, after all.
何故なら君はまだ正式な社員ではないからだ
探偵社には入社試験があり　君はまだそれを通過していない
The Agency has an entrance test,
and you haven't passed it yet.
探偵社員として
The test is to see if you have the heart and
strength to help even complete strangers.
見知らぬ人でも助ける心と強さを持っているか験す試験だ
私はきっとその試験には…
I don't think I'd pass.
気に入らないな
I don't like that.
A former killer isn't qualified
to become a good person.
元殺し屋に善人になる資格はない
君は本気でそう思っているのか
Do you truly believe that?
やぁ　ミスター芥川
Well, Mr. Akutagawa, I'd love to welcome
you aboard, but as you can see, I'm busy.
歓迎したいのは山々だが
誰の許可で床に転がってる
Who gave you permission to lie around?
今度は逃がさぬ
You aren't getting away this time.
立って戦え
Stand up and fight.
最悪の状況だ
Things couldn't get worse.
矢っ張り僕には最初から…
I was never ready to begin with.
You said earlier that you
couldn't understand me.
先刻貴様は　僕が理解できぬと云ったな
僕からすれば　貴様こそ理解できぬ
To me, you're completely incomprehensible.
その臆病な眼は　己の力も異能力も信じてない
Those fearful eyes have no faith in
your own strength or gift,
だのにいつも無謀な死闘に挑む
yet you always involve
yourself in futile battles.
Where do you get that
incoherent self-respect?
その矛盾した自尊はどこから来る
That's enough, little guy.
その辺にしておけ　小男
I don't like being ignored.
そうでなくても　俺は無視されるのが嫌い…
黙れ
Shut up.
My main course is the weretiger.
僕の主菜は人虎だ
I'd like my dessert to sit quietly.
後菓子はそこで大人しくしていろ
I hate being in second place.
俺は二番手が嫌いでな
I request our rankings be changed.
序列の変更を要求する
いいだろう
Fine.
黒獣を素手で止めるだと
Did he stop Rashoumon with his bare hands?
For your efforts, I'll teach you
the fourth secret to success.
頑張る君に成功の秘訣その四を教えてやる
要らぬ
I don't need it.
Rashoumon!
「羅生門」
「黒波濤」
Black Torrent!
Black Torrent
500,000 dollars.
五十万ドル
成功の秘訣その四だ
The fourth secret to success: Though
there are many forms of strength...
ただ強者たれ
金と権力　異能力に地位
money and influence, gifts, social status...
it helps to have all of them, the way I do.
強さの種類は一つではないが
まぁ　俺のように凡てを持つのが無難だな
虎がいない
The tiger's gone.
何が強者だ
Strength my ass!
Money and gifts don't
exist to blow up cities.
金や異能力は地上の街を吹っ飛ばす為にあるんじゃない
Human strength exists to be shared with
those who are in the depths of despair.
人の強さは　悲しみの淵で藻掻く人に差し伸べる為にあるんだ
いかにもな誤解だな
I'm not surprised that
you'd make such a mistake.
力は弱者を助ける為にあるのではない
Strength doesn't exist to help the weak.
The very essence of money-making
is to extract value from the weak.
何故なら金儲けの本質は　弱者からの搾取だからだ
それで得た金を弱者を助ける為に使っても
To then offer that to the
weak is to repeat a pointless act,
akin to swinging a door round and round.
ドアをスイングするのと同じ反復行為だ
Strength must be used more meaningfully.
力はもっと有意義なことに使わねばならん
その為に踏み潰される命は見ない振りか
Do you pretend not to see the lives
that are snubbed out to that end?
By the snubbed out lives of the weak...
踏み潰される弱者というのは
例えば昔の君のような？
Do you mean, for example, your past self?
君の過去は調べた
I looked up your history.
君は幼少時代に二度殺されかけているね　孤児院の院長に
You were nearly killed, twice,
in your early childhood
by the president of your orphanage.
彼に蹴られて肋骨を折られた時　院長は云ったそうだな
When he kicked you and broke
your ribs, he said to you...
Compared to what your parents
did to you in your infancy,
実の両親が赤子の貴様にしたことに比べれば
this doesn't even count as violence.
この程度　暴力の内にも入らん
速度が落ちて落下コースに入ったか
We're slowing down, preparing for descent.
We have just over ten minutes until impact.
激突まであと十数分だな
I understand.
理解した
なに
What?
Stop!
待て
He ran?
逃げた…だと
先刻　貴様を理解できぬと云った台詞　取り消そう
I take back what I said about not
being able to understand you.
理解した
I understand you.
人虎　貴様はいつも誰かから生きる許可を貰う為に戦っている
Weretiger, you fight in order
to earn permission to live.
Even if that means
sacrificing your own life.
自らの命すら擲って
実に不快だ
Disgusting.
本気で思うのか　人虎
Do you honestly believe, weretiger, that
someone is out there to grant you permission?
許可を出す誰かがいると
他者の為　血を吐き戦えば
Did you think that if you put your
life on the line fighting for others,
誰かが生きる価値ありと書かれた判を押してくれると思ったか
someone will stamp a form certifying
that you deserve to live?
Where's the crime in believing that?
そう思うことの何が悪い
You're an utter disappointment.
とんだ期待外れだ
貴様がこれほどまでに愚かとは
I never expected you to be such a fool.
これでは　仮令貴様を百回殺そうと　何の戦果にもならん
I could kill you hundreds of times, and I'd
have gained no accomplishments in battle.
戦果だと？
Accomplishments in battle.
然り
Indeed.
それが唯一絶対の価値
That is the only true measure of value.
Without any accomplishments in battle,
that man would never approve of me.
戦果無き限り　あの人は僕を認めぬ
Not Dazai-san.
太宰さんは決して…
太宰さん？
Dazai-san?
How does his name fit here?
何故そこで太宰さんの名前が出るんだ
見つけたぞ　ストレイドッグス
I've found you, stray dogs.
Kyouka-chan, everyone has
strengths and weaknesses.
鏡花ちゃん
人には向き不向きがある
そして君には明らかな殺しの才能がある
You clearly have talent in killing.
だから君は探偵社員にはなれない　君はそう思ってる
You think that, therefore, you can't
become a member of the Detective Agency.
That's foolish.
まったく莫迦莫迦しい
その考えが如何に根拠薄弱か　一秒で証明して見せよう
I'll prove to you in one second how
devoid of reason that belief is.
鏡花ちゃん　君はその手で何人殺した
Kyouka-chan, how many people have
you killed with those hands?
三十五人
35.
A mere 35.
高が三十五人くらいなんだ
いいかい　鏡花ちゃん
Listen up, Kyouka-chan.
You don't know everything
about the Detective Agency.
君は探偵社の凡てを知らない
You don't know everything about yourself.
自分自身の凡ても知らない
凡てを知ることは誰にもできない
No one can know everything.
That's what we call "potential."
それを「可能性」というんだ
Even Atsushi-kun, who's
given you another chance,
君に契機をくれた敦君だって　元は災害指定猛獣だ
was originally a savage
beast, deemed a menace.
But now he's risking his own life to do what
only he can do, in order to protect this city.
でも今　彼は彼にしかできないことを命懸けでやってる
この街を守る為にね
That's it.
あれだ　貨物用昇降機
The cargo elevator.
あんな桁外れの異能力に勝てるわけない
His ability is way out of my league.
I don't stand a chance.
隙を見て端末を奪う方法を考えないと
I need to think of a way to steal
the terminal when I have a chance.
You're as foolish as ever.
相変わらず愚かな奴だ
なに
What?
This box takes us to the
inescapable deck service door.
この箱の行き先は　逃げ場無き甲板搬入口
袋小路に追い込まれたのは僕らのほうだ
We are the ones who have been cornered.
そんな
No.
この程度の輩に一度は敗れたとは　屈辱の極みだ
Nothing could be more shameful than to have
been defeated once by the likes of you.
しかも生きてよい理由を他者に求めるようなくだらぬ輩に
Especially knowing that you're so worthless
that you ask others for your own right to live.
You're right, I'm worthless.
確かに僕はくだらない
でもお前みたいに　力を誇示したいだけの殺人鬼より百倍はマシだ
But you're a murderer with no purpose
but to flaunt your strength.
I'm a hundred times better.
Say that again.
なんだと
力も地位も十分あるのに
You have plenty of power and status.
ただみんなに怖がられたいから戦うなんて
You fight just so that people fear you.
That's way more worthless.
そのほうがよほどくだらな…
Take that back!
取り消せ
僕に力も地位もあるだと？
I have power and status?
貴様を不快だと云った理由を教えてやる
I'll tell you why I called you disgusting.
それは貴様が　凡てを持っていながら
It's because you're a fool who continues to
mope about old wounds despite having everything.
そのことに気付きもせず　己が古傷に甘え続ける愚か者だからだ
なに　僕がなんだって
What?
What did you say I am?
You're blessed with your gift.
異能力に恵まれ　出逢いに恵まれ
You're blessed with friends.
With no effort and with nothing but sheer
luck, you're revered and praised by Dazai-san.
努力もぜず　ただ運だけで太宰さんに認め讃えられながら
貴様はその幸福にも気付かず　己の悲劇ばかりに浸る
You don't even understand how lucky you are.
You dwell in your own tragedy.
You're a disgusting fool!
愚物だからだ
Without any accomplishments in battle,
that man would never approve of me.
戦果なき限り　あの人は僕を認めぬ
Not Dazai-san.
太宰さんは決して…
太宰さんって
Dazai-san?
まさかお前　ずっと…
Don't tell me you've always been...
鬼遊はそろそろ終わりにしよう
That's enough of playing tag.
In less than ten minutes, the Moby Dick
will enter into an irrevocable trajectory.
あと十分足らずで「白鯨」の高度は復行限界を下回る
At that point, not even this terminal will
be able to stop it from falling into the city.
それを過ぎれば
この端末でも街への落下を防げない
Only I will survive, as I've
strengthened myself with my ability.
生き残るのは　異能力で身体強化した俺だけだ
Hey, nouveau riche, if I defeat someone as
strong as you, will I no longer be weak?
成金背広
貴様ほどの強者を倒せば　僕も弱者ではなくなるか
I'll guarantee it.
保証しよう
Then I won't regret dying
as many times as it takes.
ならばこの身がいくつ砕けようとも　惜しくはない
「羅生門」
Rashoumon! Demonic Armor!
天魔
纏鎧
異能力で体を強制操作しているのか
Is he overriding my actions with his gift?
芥川はあんなに強いのに　自分のことを弱者だと思ってる
Akutagawa is so strong, yet
he thinks of himself as weak.
He's preposterous!
だとしたら言語道断だ
How many people has his selfishness killed?
その身勝手で何人死んだと思ってる
Tiger, grant me strength once again.
虎よ
もう一度僕に力を…
あの時のように
Just like last time.
Get out of my way, weretiger!
邪魔するな　人虎
お前こそ　邪魔をするな
You get out of my way!
Dazai-san, my ass!
何が太宰さんだ
お前のほうがくだらない
You're even more worthless!
Nonsense.
笑止　僕より貴様のほうがくだらぬ
You're more worthless than I am!
面白い
This is amusing.
You're both very much alike.
君達は　実に似た者同士だ
What?!
なに
こんな奴と
Don't...
...compare me...
一緒に
...to him!
するな
黒布に鎧と外筋の役を担わせるこの技
This technique makes my black
armor double as muscle.
My body is too feeble to last.
脆弱な肉体が持たぬ
休憩か　芥川
Taking a break, Akutagawa?
Shut up.
黙れ　次は貴様だ
You're next.
制御端末が先だ
The control terminal comes first.
If this ship hits the city,
Dazai-san will be obliterated, too.
この船が街に落ちたら　太宰さんまで吹き飛ぶだろ
あの人がこの程度で死ぬものか
That man wouldn't die so easily.
道標　教えてくれ
Tiger beetle, tell me, is
there anything in this world
この世界で凡てを犠牲にする価値のあるものが
aside from family worth
sacrificing everything for?
家族以外に存在すると思うか
I'll take the book, and I'll bring
my daughter back into this world.
俺は「本」を手に入れる
そして娘をこの世に呼び戻す
娘？
Your daughter?
My wife, Zelda, unable to accept our
daughter's death, became mentally ill.
妻ゼルダは　娘の死を受け止められず　心を病み
To this day, she hides in her fantasy that
our daughter is studying abroad in London.
娘はロンドンに留学中という妄想の中に　今も逃げ込んでいる
俺はその妄想を現実にし　家族を取り戻す
I'm going to make that fantasy a reality,
and reclaim my family.
No matter what the cost is.
どんな犠牲を払っても
My wealth is dispensable.
処分可能な俺の資産
その凡てを支払う
I'll pay all of it!
桁違いだ
He's off the scales.
It's like standing in front
of a massive tornado.
まるで巨大の竜巻の前にいるみたいな…
これが　ギルドの長の覚悟
This is the will of the Guild's leader?
Akutagawa...
芥川
What?
なんだ
僕は　愚かか
Am I a fool?
あの記憶から逃げたいと思うことはくだらないか
Is it worthless of me to want
to escape from those memories?
ああ　くだらぬ
It is.
The words of your past are fundamentally
unrelated to who you are now.
何故なら　苦しめる過去の言葉と貴様は　本質的に無関係だからだ
そうか
I see.
太宰さんは　とっくにお前を認めてると思うぞ
I think Dazai-san already approved
of you a long time ago.
来い
Come!
「月下獣・半人半虎」
Beast Beneath the Moonlight!
「羅生門・天魔纏鎧」
Rashoumon Demonic Armor!
君の苦悩は君だけのものじゃない
成りたいものと向いてるものが違う時
人はどうすればいい
生き方の正解を知りたくて　誰もが戦ってる
Episode 24
If I May Shed Away
My Burden Now
何を求め戦う
どうやって生きる
答えは誰も教えてくれない
我々にあるのはただ迷う権利だけだ
次回　第二十四話
若し今日この荷物を降ろして善いのなら